<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    <title>Chris Forster</title>
    <subtitle>His Web Life and Opinions</subtitle>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cforster.com" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://cforster.com/atom.xml" />
    <author>
      <name>Chris Forster</name>
      <email>cforster@syr.edu</email>
    </author>
    <id>https://cforster.com/</id>



    <updated>2022-07-18T00:12:00Z</updated>

<entry>
    <title>Are Large Language Models Operationalizations of Saussurean Structure?</title>
    
    <link rel="via" type="text/html" href="cforster.com//2022/07/on-words" />
    
    <id>tag:cforster.com,2022-07-18:/2022/07/on-words</id>
    <updated>2022-07-18T00:12:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;The title’s a bit ugly, but it captures the question I’m trying to ask: can various computational representations of language/meaning be usefully understood as “operationalizations” of what Ferdinand de Saussure describes as structure or
    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Forster</name>
    </author>
    
    
    <content type="html">
    	&lt;p&gt;The title’s a bit ugly, but it captures the question I’m trying to ask: can various computational representations of language/meaning be usefully understood as “operationalizations” of what Ferdinand de Saussure describes as structure or &lt;em&gt;langue&lt;/em&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Course in General Linguistics&lt;/em&gt; (1916). Given Saussure’s influence in literary theory and the humanities more broadly,&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;I leave aside entirely Saussure’s impact in &lt;em&gt;linguistics&lt;/em&gt;, though my sense is that Saussure was more put aside than superseded in linguistics. Insofar as computational approaches to language over the last twenty years represent something like a turn away from the dominance of Chomskyan grammar in the second half of the twentieth century, and towards something grounded in statistics, Saussure does seem a fitting figure.&lt;/span&gt; I think this would be a useful way of enabling thinking about computational representations of meaning, from word embeddings (about which I’ll say more) to “large language models” and related technologies that have been kind of amazing to watch develop over the last year (I’m thinking of GPT-3, of DALL-E… all those kind of jaw dropping pictures circulating on twitter over the past few months).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m writing to see if this observation 1) is true, and 2) is useful. (I’m more uncertain of the latter than the former.) It seems to me that Saussure’s account of language and meaning is a useful analogue to computational models of meaning because it describes meaning as &lt;strong&gt;essentially differential&lt;/strong&gt;. (Or, in a Derridean vein, &lt;em&gt;différantial&lt;/em&gt;? … I want LLMs to bring theory back! Which is what Ted Underwood predicted… &lt;a href=&#34;https://tedunderwood.com/2013/08/04/interesting-times-for-literary-theory/&#34;&gt;nearly a &lt;em&gt;decade&lt;/em&gt; ago&lt;/a&gt;!) For instance, in trying to explain models like DALL-E to someone the other day, I was asked: “So, does it [DALL-E] invent something new, or just recombine things from the internet?”&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;Underwood captures a version of this in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Ted_Underwood/status/1512813693049917441&#34;&gt;mini-thread invoking Coleridge’s distinction between fancy and imagination from the &lt;em&gt;Biographia Literaria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; This question captures the challenge of thinking about, and thinking through, these models. I don’t think such models really do either; they don’t spontaneously create new images &lt;em&gt;ex nihilo&lt;/em&gt; nor do they simply remix the already existing. But of course, this binary (creation/recombination) seems an impoverished way of thinking about how a human generates a text. The rather long and extensive, and now decades old, tradition of thinking about elements of culture through Saussure offers a valuable way out of this impasse. This very question was equally at stake in such (post)structuralist slogans as Roland Barthes’s insistence that “it is language which speaks, not the author” &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;barthes_death_1977&#34;&gt;(Barthes 143)&lt;/span&gt; (a connection Underwood has also made &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Ted_Underwood/status/1536681676125913088&#34;&gt;[cite]&lt;/a&gt;). At the very least, thinking about these models as Saussurean structures (rather than as, say, &lt;em&gt;intelligences&lt;/em&gt;) can forestall some of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2022/06/11/google-ai-lamda-blake-lemoine/&#34;&gt;worst ways&lt;/a&gt; of trying to understand what these models output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structuralist overtones of much computationally-driven cultural work has often come in a Lévi-Straussian flavor, mixed with a desire for a more empirically grounded work. But that is, I think, only one half (and, I think, the less influential half) of how structuralism, and the “theory moment,” shaped literary theory (to stick to the area with which I’m most familiar). Returning to Saussure gives an opportunity to enrich and complicate the structuralist/computational connection. I want to suggest that these models offer an opportunity to highlight the essentially &lt;em&gt;quantitative&lt;/em&gt; element that underlies Saussure and, indeed, remains implicit in much post-Saussurean and poststructuralist thinking. This quantitative element is essential, but largely latent, in Saussure’s description of the arbitrary character of the sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the broad strokes (and perhaps even the narrow strokes) of the connections between computational models of language (including “large language models”) and structuralism seem like they’ve been in the ether for a while. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
Sure, they didn&#39;t want to be proved right &lt;em&gt;like this.&lt;/em&gt; But that&#39;s always true of prophecy. Poets and literary critics are still morally required to take a victory lap for predicting that “it is language which speaks, not the author.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Exw4VGXGZs&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Exw4VGXGZs&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
— Ted Underwood (&lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;Ted_Underwood&#34;&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Ted_Underwood?&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Ted_Underwood/status/1536681676125913088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 14, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
“Lang.” does seem better for current AI than “intelligence.” But interesting how “lang.” here closer to Saussure&#39;s “langue” (abstract signifying system) than “parole” (actual utterances). Isn&#39;t lang used as “foundation” model bc it provides a useful starterpack signifying system?
&lt;/p&gt;
— Ryan Heuser (&lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;quadrismegistus&#34;&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;quadrismegistus?&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/quadrismegistus/status/1526110404111437826?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;May 16, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
structuralism is back baby!! &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/60gRTTgBQc&#34;&gt;https://t.co/60gRTTgBQc&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
— Robin Manley (&lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;_robinmanley&#34;&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;_robinmanley?&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_robinmanley/status/1518989544544038912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 26, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tweets all to some extent express the idea that there is something about language models/neural networks/“artificial intelligence” that recalls structuralism. Bernard Dionysus Geohegan’s work on cybernetics and structuralism and his forthcoming book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dukeupress.edu/code&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Code: From Information Theory to French Theory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; promises to enrich the deeper history of this connection; but I want to focus on something far more modest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, I started this post originally to talk about something much narrower—J. R. Firth, and the theorization of word embedding vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-j.-r.-firth-as-theoretical-inspiration-for-word-embedding-vectors&#34;&gt;On J. R. Firth as Theoretical Inspiration for Word Embedding Vectors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word embeddings, or word embedding vectors (among other methods), are a way of representing the meaning of a word with a series of numbers. The basic idea of word embeddings is to treat a word as a point in (multidimensional) “space.”&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;Listen, writing about these things means going out on a limb. If there is something grossly wrong this summary, let me know.&lt;/span&gt; A word’s position in space reflects, or represents, its meaning. Most simply: words with similar meanings should be grouped together in the same space. &lt;em&gt;Schnauzers&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;bulldogs&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;poodles&lt;/em&gt; might all be constellated around &lt;em&gt;dog&lt;/em&gt;. A lovely idea, right? But how to do it? (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ryanheuser.org/word-vectors/&#34;&gt;Ryan Heuser’s posts on word vectors&lt;/a&gt; were an invaluable resource when I first read them.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key techniques for generating these vectors &lt;em&gt;embed&lt;/em&gt; a word in this “semantic” space by looking at the terms that surround it. If you had a massive dataset and looked at the words that appear “near” (say, within 2 or 3 words) the terms for dog breeds I just mentioned, you would find terms for the sort of things dogs do—wag tails, fetch bones, mark territory, prick up their ears, get dewormed, and so on.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Now we can use those terms to generate the coordinates for each of our dog-related terms. Since words with similar meanings have similar collocates, this should get us our space, right? Carrying this intuition further, we would assume that &lt;em&gt;cat&lt;/em&gt; as a term will not be closer in this space to &lt;em&gt;bulldog&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;schaunzer&lt;/em&gt; than both of those terms will be to &lt;em&gt;dog&lt;/em&gt;. But cat will be closer to &lt;em&gt;dog&lt;/em&gt; (and any other words in that “neighborhood”) than it is to say “Constitution” or “fascism” (to pick two words chosen entirely without regard to contemporary events here in the summer of 2022).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From collocation of words to locations of vectors—that’s the idea.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;All fine for the English professor to say; but transforming collocation counts into a meaningful representation is going to involve some linear algebra.&lt;/span&gt; When people were first oohing and aahing over these things (back in 2015), one could use some relatively straightforward vector algebra to do things like querying for the resulting term if one started with the position of &lt;em&gt;king&lt;/em&gt;, subtracted the embedding vector representing &lt;em&gt;man&lt;/em&gt;, and added in the vector for &lt;em&gt;woman&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;code&gt;king - man + queen&lt;/code&gt; produced, &lt;code&gt;queen&lt;/code&gt;, which is pretty impressive… or, it was in 2015. (Compared to the outputs of DALL-E and GPT-3, this all seems wonderfully quaint.)&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reading the literature about word embedding vectors, the most frequently cited theoretical inspiration for this approach to meaning is the British linguistic J. R. Firth. He is quoted with great frequency for asserting that “You shall know a word by the company it keeps!” in “A Synopsis of Linguistic Theory” &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;firth_synopsis_1968&#34;&gt;(179)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;This essay can be a bit tricky to track down. If you’d like a PDF, email/DM me.&lt;/span&gt; Firth insists that meaning be grounded in a “context of situation,” a concept that sounds vaguely related to the “company [a word] keeps,” but the former is a much broader idea. And for all the citations Firth gets as inspiration for semantic word vectors, they seem rather far afield of Firth’s central preoccupations in “A Synopsis.” Indeed, reading beyond this passage, one finds very little to help you reason about collocations quantitatively.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref3&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firth, in short, provides only the thinnest veneer of theoretical justification for what word embeddings are, and how they work. An essay by Mikael Brunila and Jack LaViolette (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2205.07750&#34;&gt;a May 2022 preprint&lt;/a&gt;) summarizes this situation well, discussing J. R. Firth alongside Zelig Harris as the theoretical inspirations for word embeddings. As they note, in the word embedding literature “despite an explosion of citations… this interest [in Firth] has not been very engaged.” Rather, Firth has been invoked in order to “lend theoretical authority to a field that struggles to lift its gaze from the latest state-of-the-art numbers” &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;brunila_what_2022&#34;&gt;(Brunila and LaViolette)&lt;/span&gt;. If you come to Firth from discussions of word embeddings (as I did), you may feel rather puzzled (as I did!), looking (in vain!) for collocation calculations among talk of “context of situation” and the occasional citation of Alfred North Whitehead (!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason Firth’s thinking, or at least Firth’s slogan that meaning is related to the “company [a word] keeps,” is so often cited is because the technique used by &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/archive/p/word2vec/&#34;&gt;word2vec&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most influential word embedding models, uses a small window of collocates to generate its vectors. But this window is more a detail of implementation, rather than an essential element in how one might imagine word embedding models (indeed, other word embeddings—including &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlp.stanford.edu/projects/glove/&#34;&gt;GloVe&lt;/a&gt;, unless I’m mistaken, don’t use this window). If the core insight of word vectors is to imagine &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; as a point in large dimensional space, then Firth may not be the most useful theoretical inspiration. The space these models create is generated by representing a term not simply in relation to its collocates, but also in relation to all the terms in the vocabulary. The collocates embed a term in a space that is generated (originally) by all the terms in the model’s vocabulary. It is the sum total of all the terms that are used, and then how they used in relation to one another, that really allows meaning to be represented and mapped in this spatial way.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref4&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we’re not just talking about “the company [a word] keeps,” we’re talking about a method for generating a “space.” Yet even representing meaning as points in &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt; is, to some degree a technical detail (or, perhaps, a metaphor). Trying to imagine what a 300-dimensional word embedding model “looks like” is, of course, impossible.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;I recall a rather funny comment somewhere: asked how to imagine, say, a twelve-dimensional space, a mathematician responded: “Imagine a three dimensional space. Now concentrate while saying 12 loudly.”&lt;/span&gt; While the algorithms and measures of distance used in such models have geometrical interpretations that make them easier to understand, what we’re really talking about is not “space” as we (non-mathematicians) visualize or imagine it. Or, we might say, it is very easy to imagine what a 300-dimensional word embedding looks like: it looks like a spreadsheet with 300 columns, and rows for each term in the vocabulary. What these models are quantifying and representing is not space, but the &lt;em&gt;differences&lt;/em&gt; among the terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is my point: if these models are best understood as representing language (or meaning) as a system of differences, then it is Saussure, far more than Firth, who provides something like a theoretical description of this model. A set of word embedding vectors, or indeed most language models as I (in my inexpert way understand them) look very much like what Saussure calls “a system of pure values” &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;saussure_course_1986&#34;&gt;(155)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saussure&#34;&gt;Saussure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s talk Saussure for a moment. My goal here is simply to highlight the (I think) often ignored &lt;em&gt;quantitative&lt;/em&gt; element that is implicit in Saussure’s model of meaning, in order to ask whether contemporary, computational language models might be described as operationalized instances of a Saussurean model of meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central to Saussure’s description of language is a rejection of any attempt to treat it as a list-like aggregation of names paired with concepts/ideas. One instead had to treat the system as a whole: “A language is a system in which all the elements fit together, and in which the value of any one element depends on the simultaneous coexistence of all the others” &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;saussure_course_1986&#34;&gt;(Saussure et al. 159)&lt;/span&gt;. “Value” here is a slightly slippery term. Saussure calls the exchange of a word for an idea &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt;, but the relationship a word has to the rest of the words in a language its &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt;. A value is determined not in the relationship between a word and the object it names, but in relationship to the other words within a language/system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saussure offers an illuminating example of how &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt; differs from &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The French word &lt;em&gt;mouton&lt;/em&gt; may have the same meaning as the English word &lt;em&gt;sheep&lt;/em&gt;; but it does not have the same value. There are various reasons for this, but in particular the fact that the English word for the meat of this animal, as prepared and served for a meal, is not &lt;em&gt;sheep&lt;/em&gt; but &lt;em&gt;mutton&lt;/em&gt;. The difference in value between &lt;em&gt;sheep&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;mouton&lt;/em&gt; hinges on the fact that in English there is also another word &lt;em&gt;mutton&lt;/em&gt; for the meat, whereas &lt;em&gt;mouton&lt;/em&gt; in French covers both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a given a language, all the words which express neighboring ideas help to define one another’s meaning. Each set of synonyms like &lt;em&gt;redouter&lt;/em&gt; (‘to dread’), &lt;em&gt;craindre&lt;/em&gt; (‘to fear’), &lt;em&gt;avoir peur&lt;/em&gt; (‘to be afraid’) has its particular value only because they strand in contrast with one another. If &lt;em&gt;redouter&lt;/em&gt; (‘to dread’) did not exist, its content would be shared out among its competitors… So the value of any given word is determined by what other words there are in that particular area of the vocabulary. &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;saussure_course_1986&#34;&gt;(160)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Values don’t pre-exist the system, waiting to be labeled; they are, as we say, produced by the language. The key I want to highlight, however, is how strongly this description resonates with word vectors (and, I think, with computational models of language/meaning more broadly). Saussure’s language here—of a “neighborhood” of terms; of a “particular area of the vocabulary”—anticipates models of meaning as vector space. Saussure’s description here is, I think, a better description/theorization of word-embedding vectors (and similar models) than Firth’s “company it keeps” slogan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a discussion of differences in inflection systems and verb tenses across language (as another example, along the &lt;em&gt;mutton&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;mouton&lt;/em&gt; distinction, of how values are produced by language), Saussure summarizes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all these cases what we find, instead of &lt;em&gt;ideas&lt;/em&gt; given in advance, are &lt;em&gt;values&lt;/em&gt; emanating from a linguistic system. If we say that these values correspond to certain concepts, it must be understood that the concepts in question are purely differential. That is to say they are concepts defined not positively, in terms of their content, but negatively by contrast with other items in the same system. What characterizes each most exactly is being whatever the others are not. &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;saussure_course_1986&#34;&gt;(162)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reflects what Saussure articulates as a “paradoxical principle”: the doubleness of all values. &lt;strong&gt;One&lt;/strong&gt;: a value can be located within a system of like/comparable values; &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt;, value can also be exchanged that for something dissimilar. Saussure’s example is money, which can be compared to other monetary values quantitatively, or exchanged for some object/commodity. In language a word can be compared to other like values (i.e. to other words)—but also “exchanged” for something dissimilar (a concept or an idea). When Saussure articulates this idea, he simply asserted that comparing words to other words is somehow akin to the quantitative comparison of one monetary value to another. Vector-space representations of language, I think we have a more direct model of what this could actually look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/images/saussure_signs.png&#34; alt=&#34;Saussure’s image of a language as a system.&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;Saussure’s image of a language as a system.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This crude image of signs relating to one another in a total system seems to show each term relating only to its neighbors—in a sort of one dimensional line. But the idea, I take it, is that each term is a single location within a much larger space, and is defined only by its difference from all the other terms. Some terms, of course, may be nearer and further—but the space is defined by all the terms, by the &lt;em&gt;langue&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This understanding of meaning as &lt;em&gt;differential&lt;/em&gt;, as produced by a value’s (quasi-quantitative) difference from other (quasi-quantiative) values, is at the heart of—indeed, I’m suggesting it &lt;em&gt;is the heart&lt;/em&gt; of—the Saussurean model of meaning. Saussure, of course, doesn’t quantify his values, and doesn’t seem to imagine the uses or benefits of doing so. But the idea of meaning as essentially differential is, I think, a fundamentally quantitative (even if only implicitly so) concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of intro lit theory classes (of the sort that I teach with some regularity), I think the stress is sometimes placed on Saussure’s insistence on the arbitrary character of the sign. From this arbitrariness stems the antifoundationalism that is a hallmark of poststructuralism. But, for my money (and, probably, Derrida’s), it is the claim that languagef is a system of differences without any positive values that is the genuinely interesting element of the &lt;em&gt;Course in General Linguistics&lt;/em&gt;. After all, the observation that the signifier is “arbitrary” is neither novel to Saussure, nor particularly shocking. Saussure’s insight is that if, as seems incontestably obvious, there is no necessary relationship between what he calls signifier and signified (a fact well evidenced by the existence of different languages)&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;Saussure does spend some a brief passage rejecting any attempt to ground meaning in onomatopoeia &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;saussure_course_1986&#34;&gt;(101–02)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;, then arbitrary &lt;em&gt;means&lt;/em&gt; differential: “the terms &lt;em&gt;arbitrary&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;differential&lt;/em&gt; designate two correlative principles” &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;saussure_course_1986&#34;&gt;(Saussure et al. 163)&lt;/span&gt;. Large language models represent an operationalization of this idea, they lend calculations to what was always already (ahem) a quantitative concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;So what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve contended that Saussure offers a better/richer/more descriptive theoretical account of word embeddings rather than Firth. But I’ve insisted on this point at such length because Saussure also offers a more recognizable point of reference a wide range of things in the humanities influenced by structuralism and poststructuralism (the sort things that folks encounter in humanities classes like “literary theory”). If we can recognize large language models are an odd combination of Saussurean &lt;em&gt;langue&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;parole&lt;/em&gt;, it seems an opportunity to leverage a long history of theory in the humanities. Does Saussure offers a richer point of transit between contemporary discussions about large language models and the history of theory?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, to approach the problem from something like the other dimension: Does seeing large language models as Saussurean structures reveal a tacit, quantitative dimension to much structuralist influenced work. Consider Judith Butler’s &lt;em&gt;Gender Trouble&lt;/em&gt;—certainly one of the most influential “theory” texts. In &lt;em&gt;Gender Trouble&lt;/em&gt;, Butler draws a distinction between their own position and structuralism. Butler writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;totality&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;closure&lt;/em&gt; of language is both presumed and contested within structuralism. Although Saussure understands the relationship of signifier and signified to be arbitrary, he places the arbitrary relation within a necessarily complete linguistic system. All linguistic terms presuppose a linguistic totality of structures, the entirety of which is presupposed and implicitly recalled for any one term to bear meaning. This quasi-Liebnizian view, in which language figures as a systemic totality, effectively suppresses the moment of difference between signifier and signified, relating and unifying that moment of arbitrariness within a totalizing field. The poststructuralist break with Saussure… refutes the claim of totality and universality and the presumption of binary structural oppositions that implicitly operate to quell the insistent ambiguity and openness of linguistic and cultural signification. &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;butler_gender_1990&#34;&gt;(40)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This distinction could offer interesting complications to the very of Saussure I’ve presented. But what I want to stress is what Butler here shares with Saussure: a commitment to the arbitrariness of the sign. The “insistent ambiguity and openness of linguistic cultural signification” that is so essential to Butler’s larger description of gender’s &lt;em&gt;performativity&lt;/em&gt;, is not less quantitative/differential than Saussure’s description of &lt;em&gt;langue&lt;/em&gt;. Such signifying phenomena—defined by iterability, by arbitrariness, by difference (or &lt;em&gt;différance&lt;/em&gt;)—imply a differential “matrix” (a term used by poststructuralists and machine learning enthusiasts alike), and so are in some sense quantitative. I’m &lt;em&gt;emphatically&lt;/em&gt; not interested in trying to actually operationalize Butler’s account of gender—to attach numbers to particular gendered signifiers, say—but it seems that Butler’s notion of gender, in desubstantializing gender, makes it instead an essentially stochastic concept. Perhaps some find that unsurprising—but this is certainly not the way I’m used to thinking about gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also think the differences between Saussurean structure and large language models can be potentially revealing. Saussure infamously insists on a rigid distinction between the abstract system that a language constitutes (&lt;em&gt;langue&lt;/em&gt;) and any particular use/event of that system (speech or &lt;em&gt;parole&lt;/em&gt;). The structuralist, in Saussure’s description, studies &lt;em&gt;langue&lt;/em&gt;, a synchronic system imagined outside of its history, rather than any particular use or &lt;em&gt;parole&lt;/em&gt;. While a vector-space model of meaning (like word embeddings) operates like &lt;em&gt;langue&lt;/em&gt;, it is built entirely out of &lt;em&gt;parole&lt;/em&gt;. These models scoop up massive amounts of text in order to transform what Saussure calls &lt;em&gt;values&lt;/em&gt; into actual numeric values. How should we understand the implications of this difference? Can we understand issues of embedded bias &lt;a href=&#34;https://nyupress.org/9781479837243/algorithms-of-oppression/&#34;&gt;described by Safiya Noble&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, as a consequence of treating &lt;em&gt;parole&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;langue&lt;/em&gt;? Does such a redescription enable our thinking in any productive way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Saussure reminds us of the inherently social location of the “intelligence” these models are able to achieve. If these models present us with uncanny images of apparent intelligence, it is useful to recall that the very “structure” that these models manage to boil down and concentrate from so many instances of &lt;em&gt;parole&lt;/em&gt; is an intelligence that we have collectively put there. David Weinberger famously insisted, in what became a sort of slogan for mid 2010s-among social network enthusiasm, that “the smartest person in the room is the room.” It’s a description of the power of networked culture. But, of course, a room is never “the smartest person” “in the room”; a room is neither smart nor a person. Weinberger’s eminently reasonable point—(crudely: that people working together have more intelligence than any individual and that networks enrich/enable this)—is fair enough, and well taken! The danger is to localize and attribute this outcome of social organization to a particular technology (here, “the room”).&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;(See also Jerome McGann, &lt;em&gt;A New Republic of Letters&lt;/em&gt;, pg. 43).&lt;/span&gt; In discussions of language models, I think we sometimes see something similar—a misattribution of collective, cultural “knowledge”/“intelligence” (of the sort that is embedded in language use) to the particular mechanism/technology for extracting/re-presenting that intelligence. A crude analogy: a pressure cook can make a mighty stock, but the flavor comes from the ingredients, not the pressure cooker. I’m inclined to see Saussure’s model of meaning as helping to remind us that what looks like “intelligence” in these models is a system of relationships that inheres in the material they’re trained on. It is the position of the points that is the source of the word embeddings power, and that position reflects how the words are used. The embeddings, or other technologies, can reveal some surprising and shocking and impressive things; they are truly remarkable. But it is the system of differences—or the odd pieces of it that are carved off and thrown into the flow of GPU-powered tensors—which is the location of the “intelligence” such models achieve, far more than than the models themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;unnumbered&#34; id=&#34;works-cited&#34;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references csl-bib-body hanging-indent&#34; data-line-spacing=&#34;2&#34; role=&#34;doc-bibliography&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-barthes_death_1977&#34; class=&#34;csl-entry&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioentry&#34;&gt;
Barthes, Roland. &lt;span&gt;“The &lt;span&gt;Death&lt;/span&gt; of the &lt;span&gt;Author&lt;/span&gt;.”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Image, &lt;span&gt;Music&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, translated by Stephen Heath, &lt;span&gt;Hill and Wang&lt;/span&gt;, 1977, pp. 142–48.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-brunila_what_2022&#34; class=&#34;csl-entry&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioentry&#34;&gt;
Brunila, Mikael, and Jack LaViolette. &lt;em&gt;What Company Do Words Keep? &lt;span&gt;Revisiting&lt;/span&gt; the Distributional Semantics of &lt;span&gt;J&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span&gt;R&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span&gt;Firth&lt;/span&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;span&gt;Zellig Harris&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. arXiv:2205.07750, &lt;span&gt;arXiv&lt;/span&gt;, 16 May 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2205.07750&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2205.07750&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-butler_gender_1990&#34; class=&#34;csl-entry&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioentry&#34;&gt;
Butler, Judith. &lt;em&gt;Gender &lt;span&gt;Trouble&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span&gt;Feminism&lt;/span&gt; and the &lt;span&gt;Subversion&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span&gt;Identity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;span&gt;Routledge&lt;/span&gt;, 1990.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-firth_synopsis_1968&#34; class=&#34;csl-entry&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioentry&#34;&gt;
Firth, J. R. &lt;span&gt;“A Synopsis of Linguistic Theory, 1930-55.”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Selected &lt;span&gt;Papers&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span&gt;J&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span&gt;R&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span&gt;Firth&lt;/span&gt; 1952-59&lt;/em&gt;, edited by F. R. Palmer, &lt;span&gt;Indiana University Press&lt;/span&gt;, 1968, pp. 168–205.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-saussure_course_1986&#34; class=&#34;csl-entry&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioentry&#34;&gt;
Saussure, Ferdinand de, et al. &lt;em&gt;Course in general linguistics&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;span&gt;Open Court&lt;/span&gt;, 1986.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;These sorts of intuitions—our sense of what terms are likely to be near the word “dog,” for example—crop up frequently in discussions of these methods. They offer useful “just so” stories that inspire these methods; yet it is not clear to me that these useful examples are true. We know that dogs do all those things I mentioned—but a quick look at the 296 times the term “dog” appears in the English texts in Andrew Piper’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://txtlab.org/2016/01/txtlab450-a-data-set-of-multilingual-novels-for-teaching-and-research/&#34;&gt;txtLab450&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t show any of those things. In those 296 references, within a small window of nearby terms, a dog wags its tail only once; never does a dog fetch. Dogs twice dig up bones (though only metaphorical dogs, digging metaphorical bones). My point is simply that as we reason about how these sorts of methods work, we often rely upon some reasonable intuition. Yet those reasonable intuitions don’t always seem to be supported by the method, and may paper over how genuinely alien these methods are to our basic intuitions.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that example seems carefully chosen. Following &lt;a href=&#34;https://douglasduhaime.com/posts/clustering-semantic-vectors.html&#34;&gt;Douglas Duhaime’s helpful tips&lt;/a&gt;, and this &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/analytics-vidhya/basics-of-using-pre-trained-glove-vectors-in-python-d38905f356db&#34;&gt;medium post&lt;/a&gt;, we can easily reproduce it. But my dog examples &lt;em&gt;do not&lt;/em&gt; work. If we try something the words nearest the vector produced &lt;code&gt;bulldog - dog + cat&lt;/code&gt; we get: &lt;code&gt;&#39;cat&#39;, &#39;myoot&#39;, &#39;bohld&#39;, &#39;js04bb&#39;, &#39;kahrd&#39;, &#39;kd96&#39;, &#39;rw95&#39;, &#39;greg.wilcoxdailynews.com&#39;&lt;/code&gt;, so… yeah.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone looking for the full context of the original quote. Here it is, including an interesting invocation of Wittgenstein:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;placing&lt;/em&gt; of a &lt;em&gt;text&lt;/em&gt; as a constituent in a context of situation contributes to the statement of meanign since situations are set up to recognize &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt;. As Wittgenstein says, “the meaning of words lies in tehir use.” The day-to-day practice of palying language games recognizes customs and rules. It follows that a text in such established usage may contain sentences such as ‘Don’t be an ass!’ ‘You silly ass!’ ‘What an ass he is!’ In these examples the word &lt;em&gt;ass&lt;/em&gt; is in familiar and habitual company, commonly collocated with &lt;em&gt;you silly—&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;he is a silly—&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;don’t be such an—&lt;/em&gt;. You shall know a word by the company it keeps! One of the meanings of &lt;em&gt;ass&lt;/em&gt; is its habitual collocation with such other words as those quoted. Though Wittgenstein was dealing with another problem, he also recognizes the plain face-value, the physiogonomy of words. ‘The sentence is composed of the words and that is enough.’ &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;firth_synopsis_1968&#34;&gt;(Firth 179)&lt;/span&gt;.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Key to word embeddings is reducing the dimensionality of this representation. This means that a set of texts which may feature a vocabulary in the hundreds of thousands (or greater!) can be represented with a “mere” few hundred dimensions (the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nlp.stanford.edu/projects/glove/&#34;&gt;pretrained GloVe embeddings&lt;/a&gt; are offered in 50, 100, 200, and 300 dimension versions). Like the most sophisticated language models and image generators (like GPT-3, DALL-E), these embeddings are generated (“learned”) using neural networks to reduce their dimensionality. A thing I still don’t understand: if the complete model were computationally tractable, would it be superior to using this significantly smaller model? Or, in reducing the dimensionality, do these models help make the vectors more “meaningful” by “squishing” things closer together, and so making the meaning more apparent to the various ways in which the model can be queried?&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </content>
</entry>


<entry>
    <title>Two Cheers for Banned Books Week</title>
    
    <link rel="via" type="text/html" href="cforster.com//2015/09/banned-books" />
    
    <id>tag:cforster.com,2015-09-30:/2015/09/banned-books</id>
    <updated>2015-09-30T00:12:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;My title, recalling E. M. Forster’s (no relation, sadly) &lt;em&gt;Two Cheers for Democracy&lt;/em&gt;, might be too generous. I can’t imagine mustering more than two cheers for anything. Two is probably the utter limit of m
    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Forster</name>
    </author>
    
    
    <content type="html">
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;My title, recalling E. M. Forster’s (no relation, sadly) &lt;em&gt;Two Cheers for Democracy&lt;/em&gt;, might be too generous. I can’t imagine mustering more than two cheers for anything. Two is probably the utter limit of my cheering.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is “Banned Books Week” anarchronistic? That’s the claim of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/arts/culturebox/2015/09/banned_books_week_no_one_bans_books_anymore_and_censorship_of_books_is_incredibly.single.html&#34;&gt;this article at Slate&lt;/a&gt;. John Overholt, in &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/john_overholt/status/648471105204830208&#34;&gt;a single tweet&lt;/a&gt;, manages to voice what I think are all the most pressing complaints about such a perspective:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
A. “We won” is a huge oversimplification.
B. It&#39;s only true for the narrowest definition of ban.
C. They keep trying. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/iHo3BNbGx9&#34;&gt;http://t.co/iHo3BNbGx9&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
— John Overholt (&lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;john_overholt&#34;&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;john_overholt?&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/john_overholt/status/648471105204830208&#34;&gt;September 28, 2015&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, as someone who spends quite a bit of time trying to think about what early-twentieth century censorship means, there is an important grain of truth in the Slate piece that is worth preserving, even if declarations of “Mission Accomplished” feel premature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of book banning conjures images of state censorship and book burning—images one can find in abundance, for instance, in Kevin Birmingham’s wonderful account &lt;em&gt;Ulysses&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nybooks.com/articles/archives/2015/apr/23/ulysses-its-still-scandal/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Most Dangerous Book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; images of court rooms where lawyers make grand appeals to &lt;em&gt;literary value&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;freedom of expression&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;I pass over in silence distinctions between &lt;em&gt;books&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;literature&lt;/em&gt;…&lt;/span&gt; The scene that Michelle Anne Schingler describes, at &lt;a href=&#34;http://bookriot.com/2015/09/29/hey-slate-banned-books-week-isnt-crock/&#34;&gt;Book Riot&lt;/a&gt;, however is a very different one. Schingler wastes no time in affirming “No,” book banning is not simply over. Her examples all concern libraries; and indeed as Graham contends in her piece at Slate, the most recent cases that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bannedbooksweek.org/about&#34;&gt;Banned Books website&lt;/a&gt; cites all concern attempts to limit or remove books from library collections or school settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Graham declares “we won,” that “book banning” is over, this is indeed (as Overholt suggests) an oversimplification. It imagines a single struggle, which reaches some sort of crisis, and ends. Graham is offering a narrative very close to that recounted by Charles Rembar in his memoir &lt;em&gt;The End of Obscenity&lt;/em&gt;. Rembar was the defense attorney during many of the key 1960s obscenity trials in the United States, and his memoir wonderfully charts the erosion of state censorship in the period. Suppression of books on grounds of obscenity, Rembar suggests (I think, rightly), ends after the trials of &lt;em&gt;Lady Chatterley’s Lover&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Tropic of Cancer&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Fanny Hill&lt;/em&gt; in the United States. Starting in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oyez.org/cases/1950-1959/1956/1956_582&#34;&gt;Roth v. United States&lt;/a&gt;, and culminating ultimately in the so-called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miller_test&#34;&gt;“Miller Test”&lt;/a&gt;, American jurisprudence evolves a set of standards that have the effect of ending the censorship of books on the grounds of obscenity.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;In English jurisprudence, the 1959 reform of the Obscene Publications Act (which enabled publication of Lawrence’s &lt;em&gt;Lady Chatterley&lt;/em&gt; by Penguin) plays the same role as the court cases discussed by Rembar.&lt;/span&gt; After those trials, it has proved essentially impossible for a book to be banned on grounds of obscenity; contract, libel, and copyright all continue to shape cultural production in important ways (the latter especially so), but obscenity and its particular brand of state-controlled book burning is indeed over. The Miller standard may justifiably be celebrated as a sort of liberal triumph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://images.all-free-download.com/images/graphiclarge/miller_logo_29850.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Miller Logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;Miller Logo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And boy, do we love to tell this story. Birmingham offers a version in his account of &lt;em&gt;Ulysses&lt;/em&gt;; we get a sort of version in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1049402/&#34;&gt;movies about Allen Ginsberg’s “Howl”&lt;/a&gt;; or in TV movies about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0757175/&#34;&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Chatterley&lt;/em&gt; trial&lt;/a&gt;. Folks love this tale of heroic lawyers fighting on behalf of great works of literature, against philistine puritans—figures like Anthony Comstock or William Joynson-Hicks (more commonly called simply, “Jix”). We tell very similar stories about Elvis and his hips, or Lenny Bruce and his comedy—tales where transgression and freedom contend with (usually comicly absurd) conservatism. (We even tell a version of this story about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Footloose_(1984_film)&#34;&gt;dancing in small towns&lt;/a&gt;.) It’s usually a narrative of triumph, told by liberal proponents who indeed end by declaring “We won.” And, as history, it is usually an oversimplication.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;For one thing (and this is a hobby horse of mine), it tends to remove books from a broader media history which shapes what it means to “ban” a “book.” I have a different story of my own, about the place of literature in the changing media ecology of the long twentieth century… but that’s another tale for another time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/e/e4/FootloosePoster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Footloose&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;Footloose&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Banned Books Week” conflates two narratives, perhaps deliberately. It inserts present instances of political struggle which involve books, particularly (like those described by Schingler) around libraries, into a longer history of book banning. It is, in some ways, a savvy rhetorical move to align parents who want to limit access to particular titles with Anthony Comstock and similar figures (after all, who wants to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=20jbY6awlTw&#34;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt;). But this conflation also has the, I think unfortunate, effect of casting contemporary debates about education and the meaning of “the public” as matters of “banning books.” I think it makes more sense to understand &lt;a href=&#34;http://bannedbooks.world.edu/2012/01/22/banned-books-awareness-beloved/&#34;&gt;attempts to limit access to Toni Morrison’s &lt;em&gt;Beloved&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, not as a debate about book censorship continuous with the suppression of &lt;em&gt;Ulysses&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Lady Chatterley’s Lover&lt;/em&gt;, but as part of the same political struggle over &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/whitewashing-civil-war-history-for-young-minds/2015/07/06/1168226c-2415-11e5-b77f-eb13a215f593_story.html&#34;&gt;how to teach the causes of the American Civil War&lt;/a&gt;, or even &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/23/education/texas-education-board-flags-biology-textbook-over-evolution-concerns.html&#34;&gt;whether to mention evolution&lt;/a&gt;. These are debates about books; but more fundamentally they are debates about education and, more importantly, debates about &lt;em&gt;the public&lt;/em&gt;. They ask not, “Should this book be legally available?” but “Should &lt;em&gt;my children&lt;/em&gt; learn this?” or “Should &lt;em&gt;my tax dollars&lt;/em&gt; pay for this?” Defending against the active defunding of public goods by appealing to the “freedom to read,” seems to me, to be a tactic of ambivalent value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When “Banned Books Week” began in 1982, the heroic age of the struggle against state censorship of books in the United States was already over. In 1982, rather than the State of New York seeking to prevent folks from reading &lt;em&gt;Ulysses&lt;/em&gt;, we find &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.google.com/newspapers?id=9CsdAAAAIBAJ&amp;amp;sjid=RqUEAAAAIBAJ&amp;amp;pg=6717%2C5959414&#34;&gt;the Moral Majority complaining about works like &lt;em&gt;Our Bodies, Our Selves&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This concern with women’s sexuality and health is uncannily recalled when earlier this month a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wbir.com/story/news/local/2015/09/07/local-mom-objects--controversial-book--summer-reading-list/71843596/&#34;&gt;Knoxville parent complained&lt;/a&gt; about the explict references to women’s bodies in the &lt;em&gt;The Immortal Life of Henrietta Lacks&lt;/em&gt;. Is this debate about women’s sexual health and knowledge, either in the early 1980s or now, best understood as a debate about books? Or does it have more in common with a history that, as this moment, materializes as an effort to defund Planned Parenthood?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schingler writers, “Reading only about people our parents and pastors are comfortable with isn’t an education, it’s an echo-chamber.” I agree. Reading is a wonderful and potentially transformative experience. It should be celebrated and defended zealously. But if we find people seeking to limit access to books, we may wonder whether their target is &lt;em&gt;books&lt;/em&gt; per se, or something else: &lt;em&gt;public education&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;women’s health&lt;/em&gt;, both of which require a well-funded state. Schingler writes, “Libraries are a marketplace of ideas, and if they’re going to operate in a truly democratic fashion, all ideas should be represented.” May be. But the arguments of would-be book-banners are, right now, often couched exactly in market terms—not that this or that book should not be published or legally allowed to circulate, but that &lt;em&gt;my tax dollars&lt;/em&gt; shouldn’t have to pay for it. We love the version of this conflict which is a struggle between freedom and censorship; but the conflict today is precisely one which takes place through appeals to market values—not between freedom and suppression, but &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to fund according to what criteria. The real argument today seems less about “freedom,” than about our willingness to fund and maintain a robust sense of “public goods.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a matter of rhetoric and political tactics, it perhaps makes sense to throw the weight of a long historical struggle against state censorship behind our own moment of squabbles in local school boards or funding lines in state budgets. We should be careful, though, that such rhetoric doesn’t lead us to mistake a fight about public education or women’s health or the rights of queer people for &lt;em&gt;the right to read&lt;/em&gt;. Indeed, if we could add a little nuance and history to our sense of the long struggle to publish controversial books, we might even realize that the history of books and their banning is already replete with lessons for these distinct, but not unrelated, struggles (see, for instance, the case of &lt;em&gt;The Well of Loneliness&lt;/em&gt; and its banning in England).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, two cheers for Banned Books Week and for all efforts to protect the freedom to read. The fullest possible access to the textual record is indeed a public good worthy of our time, attention, and dedication. It is not, though, the only good; it may not, at this moment, even be the most pressing one.&lt;/p&gt;

    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </content>
</entry>


<entry>
    <title>About 1400 Words of Skepticism about Markdown, and an Imagined Alternative</title>
    
    <link rel="via" type="text/html" href="cforster.com//2015/06/markdown-skepticism" />
    
    <id>tag:cforster.com,2015-06-29:/2015/06/markdown-skepticism</id>
    <updated>2015-06-29T00:12:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;’s great. Indeed, nearly all the writing I do now is in Markdown (or at least starts that way). There has been a good amount of writing about the virt
    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Forster</name>
    </author>
    
    
    <content type="html">
    	&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;’s great. Indeed, nearly all the writing I do now is in Markdown (or at least starts that way). There has been a good amount of writing about the virtues of Markdown for academic writing in particular, so I’ll just link to them here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;W. Caleb McDaniel’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://wcm1.web.rice.edu/my-academic-book-in-plain-text.html&#34;&gt;Why (and How) I Wrote My Academic Book in Plain Text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nikola Sander’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://nikolasander.com/writing-in-markdown/&#34;&gt;Writing Academic Papers in Markdown Using Sublime Text and Pandoc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dennis Tennen and Grant Wythoff’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://programminghistorian.org/lessons/sustainable-authorship-in-plain-text-using-pandoc-and-markdown&#34;&gt;Sustainable Authorship in Plaintext Using Pandoc and Markdown&lt;/a&gt; (This latter I especially recommend).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Markdown, as it stands, has some drawbacks, which become acute when you are trying to extend it to cover the needs of academic writing (or, say, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.uvic.ca/~mvp1922/otsummit/&#34;&gt;a transcription format for texts&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I will describe as “problems” all stem from the fact that Markdown remains essentially a simplified syntax for HTML. A tool like &lt;a href=&#34;http://pandoc.org&#34;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt;, which has a special (and especially powerful) flavor of Markdown all its own, helps reduce the borders between document formats. With Pandoc it becomes easy to convert &lt;code&gt;HTML&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;LaTeX&lt;/code&gt;, or Rich Text Format to Word’s &lt;code&gt;.docx&lt;/code&gt;. It could easily feel like Markdown is a universal document format—write it in Markdown, and publish as whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is a lovely dream—an easy-to-write plaintext format that can easily be output to any desired format. In reality, though, Markdown (even Pandoc’s Markdown) remains yoked to HTML, and so it suffers from some of its problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem I encounter most frequently in HTML (and in Markdown) concerns nesting a block quote within a paragraph. In short, can you have a block quote &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; a paragraph? If you’re writing HTML (or MarkDown), the answer is no—HTML treats “block quotes” as &lt;code&gt;block&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;elements&lt;/em&gt;; this means that one cannot be contained within a paragraph (this restriction does not exist in LaTeX or TEI). Yet, what could be more common in writing on works of literature? Representing poetry presents its own problems for HTML and Markdown.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;By contrast to the challenge presented by the mere fact of poetry, note the many syntaxes/tools available for fenced code blocks, syntax highlighting, and so on; Markdown, for now, remains of greatest interest to software developers and so reflects their habits and needs.&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: If you’re looking for practical advice, you can easily represent poetry in Pandoc’s markdown using &lt;a href=&#34;http://pandoc.org/README.html#line-blocks&#34;&gt;“line blocks”&lt;/a&gt;; this is not a perfect solution, but it will do for many needs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perversely, markdown also represents something of a step backward with regard to &lt;em&gt;semantics&lt;/em&gt;. If you’ve spent some time with HTML, you may have noticed how HTML5 cements a model of HTML as a semantic markup language (with, implicitly, matters of presentation controlled by CSS). That means that the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag, which long ago meant &lt;em&gt;italics&lt;/em&gt;, has since acquired semantic meaning. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.webplatform.org/wiki/html/elements/i&#34;&gt;According to the w3c&lt;/a&gt;, it should be used to “represent[] a span of text offset from its surrounding content without conveying any extra emphasis or importance, and for which the conventional typographic presentation is italic text; for example, a taxonomic designation, a technical term, an idiomatic phrase from another language, a thought, or a ship name.” Those instances where one wishes to express emphasis, use the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag. If you need to mark a title, don’t simply italicize it, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.webplatform.org/wiki/html/elements/cite&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;cite&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;But hold up, that &lt;code&gt;cite&lt;/code&gt; element obscures the distinctions we normally make between italicizing certain titles and putting others in quotation marks.&lt;/span&gt; In practice, of course, I doubt these distinctions are widely respected across the web; but all those at least &lt;em&gt;potentially&lt;/em&gt; useful distinctions are lost in markdown, whose syntax marks them all with &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt;. Markdown is, in fact, rather &lt;em&gt;unsemantic&lt;/em&gt;. (To a lesser degree, one might detect this tendency as well in the way headings—rather than &lt;code&gt;divs&lt;/code&gt;—are Markdown’s primary way of structuring a document, but I’ll stop now.) So, two points: Markdown inherits HTML’s document which includes an inability to nest block-level elements within paragraphs; in simplifying HTML, it produces a less semantically clear and rich format. (Technically, of course, one could simply include any HTML element for which Markdown offers no shortened syntax—like &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;cite&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; for example.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-solution&#34;&gt;A Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&#34;http://talk.commonmark.org/&#34;&gt;CommonMark forum&lt;/a&gt;, some folks have proposed additional syntax to fix the latter problem, and capture some of the semantic distinctions mentioned above (indeed, following the discussions over there has helped sensitize to me some of the challenges and limitations of markdown as a sort of universal format donor). So, some of these issues could be resolved through extensions or modifications of Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, given these deficits in Markdown, I wonder if it isn’t worth asking a more basic question—whether the plaintext format for “academic” writing should be so tightly yoked to HTML? If Markdown is, fundamentally, a simplified, plaintext syntax for HTML, could we imagine a similar, easy-to-write, plaintext format that wouldn’t be tied to HTML? Could we imagine, say, a format that would represent a simplification of syntax, not of HTML, but of a format better suited to the needs of representing more complex documents? Could we imagine a plaintext format that would be to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tei-c.org/index.xml&#34;&gt;TEI&lt;/a&gt;, say, what markdown is to HTML?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a format would not need to &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; particularly different from Markdown. Its syntax could overlap significantly; as in Pandoc’s Markdown format, file metadata (things like title, author, and so on) could appear (perhaps as YAML) at the front of the file (and be converted into elements within &lt;code&gt;teiHeader&lt;/code&gt;). You could still use &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;**&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;[]()&lt;/code&gt; as your chief tools; footnotes and references could be marked the same way (you could preserve Pandoc’s wonderful citation system, with such things represented as &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;refs&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in TEI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most substantive difference would not be in syntax, but in the document model. Any Markdown file can contain HTML—all HTML is valid markdown; this ensures that Markdown is never less powerful than HTML. But are the burdens of HTML worth the costs if one wishes to do scholarly/academic, or similar types of writing, in plaintext? Projects exist to repurpose Pandoc markdown for scholarly writing: Tim T. Y. Lin’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholarlymarkdown.com/Scholarly-Markdown-Guide.html#first-steps&#34;&gt;ScholarlyMarkdown&lt;/a&gt;, or Martin Fenner’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.martinfenner.org/2013/06/29/metadata-in-scholarly-markdown/&#34;&gt;similar project&lt;/a&gt;, or the workflow linked-to above, by Dennis Tennen and Grant Wythoff at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://programminghistorian.org/lessons/sustainable-authorship-in-plain-text-using-pandoc-and-markdown&#34;&gt;Programming Historian&lt;/a&gt;. What I’m imagining, though, is entirely less practical than any of these projects at the moment because it would necessitate a change in the document model into which markdown is converted. Pandoc works its magic by reading documents from a source format (through a “reader”) into an intermediary format (a format of its own that you can view by outputting &lt;code&gt;-t native&lt;/code&gt;), which it can then output (through a “writer”). Could TEI (or some representation of it), essentially, fulfill that role as intermediary format? (A Pandoc car with a TEI engine swapped in?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like writing in plaintext, but I don’t love being bound by the peculiarities that Markdown has inherited from HTML. So, it is worth considering what it is that people like about Markdown. I suspect that most of the things people like about Markdown (free, easy to write, nonproprietary, easily usable with version control, and so on), have little to do with its HTML-based document model but stem from its being a plaintext format (and the existing infrastructure of scripts/apps/workflows around markdown). TEI provides an alternative document model—indeed, a &lt;em&gt;richer&lt;/em&gt; document model. Imagine a version of Pandoc that uses TEI (or a simplified TEI subset) behind the scenes as its native format. Folks often complain about the complexity and verbosity of TEI (and XML more generally), and not without reason. I would certainly never want to &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt; TEI; but a simplified TEI syntax that could then take advantage of all the virtues of TEI, that would be something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Closing Note: At one point I wondered how easy it would be to convert markdown to TEI with Pandoc… I’ve managed to finagle a set of scripts to do that; it’s janky, but for anyone interested, it’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/c-forster/markdown2tei&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.]&lt;/p&gt;

    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </content>
</entry>


<entry>
    <title>The Podcast as a Genre</title>
    
    <link rel="via" type="text/html" href="cforster.com//2014/09/podcast-as-a-genre" />
    
    <id>tag:cforster.com,2014-09-12:/2014/09/podcast-as-a-genre</id>
    <updated>2014-09-12T00:12:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;What precisely is a podcast? I once heard a minimal definition of a podcast as an mp3 file attached to an RSS feed—which is to say, syndicated audio content on the internet. But looking around, there are plenty of podcasts that don’t mee
    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Forster</name>
    </author>
    
    
    <content type="html">
    	&lt;p&gt;What precisely is a podcast? I once heard a minimal definition of a podcast as an mp3 file attached to an RSS feed—which is to say, syndicated audio content on the internet. But looking around, there are plenty of podcasts that don’t meet this criteria: podcasts that lack an RSS feed (WHY?!?), to speak nothing of “video podcasts” (which people are apparently strill trying to make happen). “Podcast” can sometimes be used as a verb to mean something like “transmitting audio over the internet” (e.g. “Will you be podcasting that keynote lecture?”). Looking at iTunes, you realize plenty of “podcasts” are just radio shows put on the internet: iTunes’s most popular podcasts are mostly public radio fare (like “This American Life” and “Radiolab”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, the podcast is not simply a technology or a channel. I’ve been listening to podcasts for awhile now and have been curious to watch my habits slowly shift, moving away from “radio shows on the internet” (&lt;em&gt;Fresh Air&lt;/em&gt;, whenever I want it!) to something else. &lt;a href=&#34;http://niemanstoryboard.org/stories/finding-the-tribe/&#34;&gt;This piece&lt;/a&gt; looks at the “return” of podcasts as a medium, mostly considering the podcast as a business model. It does however offer this, from “Planet Money” podcaster Alex Blumberg, on what makes podcasts different:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s the most intimate of mediums. It’s even more intimate than radio. Often you’re consuming it through headphones. I feel like there’s a bond that’s created.” &lt;a href=&#34;http://niemanstoryboard.org/stories/finding-the-tribe/&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That seems entirely right to me, and it helpfully points to some of the ways that what I’ll call podcasts &lt;em&gt;as a genre&lt;/em&gt; differ from understanding podcasts as just “radio over the internet.” The “podcast” as a form blurs the line between a medium (say, a recurring, asynchronously consumed type of audio—usually neither music or fiction) and a genre. The podcast, as medium, has been enabled by readier access to bandwidth, software technologies like iTunes syndication and RSS, and developments in hardware like relatively cheap but entirely decent microphones&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;Woe unto the podcaster who relies on built-in mics on laptops and phones, for he shall receive low traffic.&lt;/span&gt; and of course the iPod. But these technologies, in their use, create a sort of gravitational pull toward a form that is less formal, more niche, and therefore oddly closer to a sort of specialized and heightened mode of casual conversation than it is to most radio genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the costs of creating and distributing recordings of folks talking into microphones gets &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; cheaper than the costs of writing/producing/reporting stories, you get a new sort of show—where folks just sit around and talk. Central to the conventions of this genre is, I think, the group of regular or semi-regular folks who sit around and talk about something. Such are Leo Laporte’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twit.tv&#34;&gt;TWIT&lt;/a&gt; podcasts; the original TWiT, one of the first podcasts I listened to, was indeed Leo Laporte sitting with folks (some of whom his listeners recognize as, like Laporte, erstwhile TechTV employees) and talking about the week’s technology news. This form tends to be parasitic on some other type of content—on news or culture (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tommerritt.com/category/shows/daily-tech-news-show/&#34;&gt;daily&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/culturegabfest.html&#34;&gt;weekly&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://digitalcampus.tv&#34;&gt;semi-regularly&lt;/a&gt;), or even on a specific film or primary text. There has to be some &lt;em&gt;reason&lt;/em&gt;, some excuse or alibi, for the conversation to exist—but the podcast offers a conversation rather than the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may not seem especially novel—after all, personality-driven “analysis” now dominates cable news. Yet cable news analysis shows usually center on a single individual, and their dominant moods are outrage or indignation or derision; they tend to be centered &lt;strong&gt;a personality&lt;/strong&gt; (variably likeable or not) who offers a “perspective.” But what a podcast offers is not a perspective (or not &lt;em&gt;chiefly&lt;/em&gt; a perspective) but something more like a performance of community. In place of the singular personality, we get personalities. A podcast tends to create characters, or caricatures, out of its hosts: for instance, Stephen Metcalf’s snobbish nostalgia for the world of print clashing regularly with Julia Turner’s culturally omnivorous techno-utopianism on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/podcasts/culturegabfest.html&#34;&gt;Slate Culturefest&lt;/a&gt; (both, of course, unfair exagerations). But in other podcasts (perhaps notably, podcasts not affiliated with any large online media presence), this develops into a sense of shared reference—something like &lt;em&gt;insiderness&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;knowingness&lt;/em&gt;. The result is that certain podcasts (the podcastiest of the podcasts by my sense of the genre) rely heavily on inside jokes. Consider the following short phrases: “Who the hell is Casey?”; “Does this look clean to you?”; “The Port Hole of Time.” To the listeners of certain podcasts, they will immediately register as inside jokes—from, respectively: &lt;a href=&#34;http://atp.fm&#34;&gt;The Accidental Tech Podcast&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://5by5.tv/b2w&#34;&gt;Back to Work&lt;/a&gt; (quoting the film &lt;em&gt;The Aviator&lt;/em&gt;, which in the universe of &lt;em&gt;Back to Work&lt;/em&gt; is frequently referered to as simply &lt;em&gt;the film&lt;/em&gt;); and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flophousepodcast.com/&#34;&gt;The Flop House&lt;/a&gt;. Listeners of these podcasts (and I listen to all of these pretty faithfully, though the truly faithful will likely fault my selections) come to recognize these, and participate in the joke. These podcasts create a universe of reference alienating to the newcomer, but comforting to the regular. And the result is just wonderful. These are my guiltiest of guilty pleasure. I try to conceal my love for them, but I cannot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That intimacy of the medium described by Alex Blumberg, created by the circumstances of consumption (on headphones or in the car&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;Are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/MP3-Player-Cassette-Adapter-Equipment/dp/B003Q9LRPO&#34;&gt;these things&lt;/a&gt; great, or what?&lt;/span&gt;), manifests in the genre as a tendency towards dense self-reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is that the topic of the podcast can increasingly seem to be just an alibi for the interactions of its hosts. I don’t really care about Apple News, but listen to &lt;a href=&#34;http://atp.fm&#34;&gt;ATP&lt;/a&gt; regularly. The greatest joy of &lt;em&gt;The Flop House&lt;/em&gt; (a “bad movie” podcast, which reviews/discussions relatively recent theatrical “flops”) is the experience of hearing the hosts &lt;em&gt;summarize the plot of a movie&lt;/em&gt; and the digressions that ensue. One emphatically does not have to have seen the movie to enjoy the podcast, and unlike a review (or even the discussions of film and TV on the &lt;em&gt;Slate Culturefest&lt;/em&gt;), it is completely beside the point whether you will see the movie at some point in the future. I suspect that I’ll never see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0804452/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bratz&lt;/em&gt; movie&lt;/a&gt;; but I shall cherish all the days of my life &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flophousepodcast.com/2008/04/episode-14-bratz/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Flop House&lt;/em&gt;’s discussion of it&lt;/a&gt;. Listen to early episodes and you’ll see that the plot summary initially presented a challenge—something they glossed over or tried to get past in order to get to the discussion (on at least one occassion they just read the Wikipedia summary of a movie). But the joy of the show is entirely in the interactions between its hosts, and so something as rote as a plot summary becomes the perfect opportunity for such interaction. It also explains why at least I find these sorts of shows more engaging than other audio content. The academic lecture, or even &lt;em&gt;Fresh Air&lt;/em&gt;-style interviews, sometimes allows distraction. But the developing conversation, and tissue of self-reference, simulates the experience of interaction rather than, say, the communication of information. (What an interview show like &lt;em&gt;Fresh Air&lt;/em&gt; lacks is the regularity of its participants; you’re usually learning something &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; a guest rather than a conversation between people who already know each other.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By foregrounding in jokes and habits of communication, the podcast turns out to be a cousin to that other “internetiest” of forms: the meme. The meme is likewise an in-joke, where the in-group is those folks who recognize the meme and understand its conventions. The humor of any individual &lt;a href=&#34;http://knowyourmeme.com/memes/doge&#34;&gt;“doge,”&lt;/a&gt; meme (remember that?) is siphoned off from the larger system of doge memes that makes any particular meme legible and funny. (A picture of a cat with some funny, misspelled words, encoutered in utter isolation, carved into the face of some alien moon millenia hence, would be funny because absurd—but it wouldn’t be a meme and wouldn’t participate in its humor.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The affective range of the podcast is much wider than that of meme, chiefly because hearing a conversation between the same set of people (semi)regularly opens more possibilities than silly pictures and block letters. (There I said it; call me elitist.) But this affective depth cuts the other way—it also suggests what I find mildly unsettling about the form, and perhaps slightly embarassing about my enjoyment of it. If I’m right that inside jokes, and a certain performance of knowing insiderness, are what separates the podcast as a genre from its radio peers, it also feels a little like media consumption as simulated friendship. Its enjoyments are those of easy familiarity and comfortable in-jokes, but with friends who aren’t yours. (You might call this the anxiety of authenticity, and I’ll just take my lumps for worrying over something as old-fashioned as authenticity.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More troublingly, that same affective register (of chummy friendship and inside jokes) seems downright insidious when you realize how overwhelmingly the list of podcasts I’ve cited here is dominanted by white guys. In so much as the pleasures and affects of the genre are those associated with those of the proverbial boys club, it is dismaying to see how much of a boy’s club it often is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a podcast? It is the humanization of the internet meme, a type of low-participation friendship, a reduced agency form of “hanging out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours in Flopitude, Chris [Last Name Witheld]&lt;/p&gt;

    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </content>
</entry>


<entry>
    <title>From New Hampshire to Harlem, by Way of London</title>
    
    <link rel="via" type="text/html" href="cforster.com//2013/10/spring-new-hampshire" />
    
    <id>tag:cforster.com,2013-10-10:/2013/10/spring-new-hampshire</id>
    <updated>2013-10-10T00:12:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;While I haven’t been vocal about it, work has continued, in off moments and stolen time, on the online edition of Claude McKay’s &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt; which I described &lt;a href=&#34;/2012/06/drill-baby-drill/&#34;&gt;some time ago&lt;/a&gt;. At the pre
    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Forster</name>
    </author>
    
    
    <content type="html">
    	&lt;p&gt;While I haven’t been vocal about it, work has continued, in off moments and stolen time, on the online edition of Claude McKay’s &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt; which I described &lt;a href=&#34;/2012/06/drill-baby-drill/&#34;&gt;some time ago&lt;/a&gt;. At the present moment, &lt;a href=&#34;http://roopikarisam.com/&#34;&gt;Roopika Risam&lt;/a&gt; and I have collected nearly all the textual variants and have marked them up in TEI; we added (as yet unproofread) versions of early reviews and other supplemental material (and still more is being hunted down and added); and there is enough XSLT and CSS to hold the whole thing together, more or less. It is very much still a work in progress, but you can see the current state of its progress &lt;a href=&#34;http://harlemshadows.org/beta/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process has also been an opportunity to understand the textual history of the poems of &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;, including the relationship of the collection &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt; to McKay’s earlier collection &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt;. The Jamaican poet who travels to rural Kansas in order to pursue a degree in agriculture and ends up being one of the early voices of Harlem Renaissance, manages to do so by passing through not only Harlem, but New Hampshire and, crucially, London. &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; was how many readers first encountered McKay (including readers like Charlie Chaplin and Hubert Harrison), and the collection offers a valuable first draft of &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collection &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; was first published in 1920. Its “Acknowledgments” page notes two facts which underscore this volume’s importance in the emergence of &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/harlem-shadows/spring_acknowledgments.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/harlem-shadows/spring_acknowledgments.png&#34; alt=&#34;Acknowledgments are due to the Editors of The Seven Arts, the American Pearsons and The Liberator, where, as in the current issue of The Cambrdige Magazine a number of the poems included in this volume have appeared. An American edition is being published simultaneously by Alfred A. Knopf, 220 West Forty-second Street, New York.&#34; title=&#34;Acknowledgments in Spring in New Hampshire&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, when &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; appeared, an American edition of was clearly imagined as immiment. But the American edition, purportedly “being published simultaneously by Alfred A. Knopf,” never materialized. What did appear, two years later (published by Harcourt, Brace, and Co) was &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt; is substantially indebted to &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;About one third of &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;’s poems appear in &lt;em&gt;Spring&lt;/em&gt;, among them “Tropics in New York,” “The Barrier,” “North and South,” “Harlem Shadows,” “The Harlem Dancer,” and “The Lynching.”&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; in turn is less an origin than another gathering point for poems culled from elsewhere; this is especially the case of a large selection of poems which appear in the Summer 1920 issue of &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt;. This latter includes 23 of &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt;’s 31 poems. And, with the exception of the dedication of “Spring in New Hampshire” (dedicated in &lt;em&gt;Spring&lt;/em&gt; to “J. L. J. F. E.”&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;This would almost certainly be Dutch bibliophile, and the man in part responsible for McKay’s trip to London, J. L. J. F. Ezerman (Gosciak 117).&lt;/span&gt;), there are &lt;em&gt;no textual differences&lt;/em&gt; between the poems as they appear in &lt;em&gt;CM&lt;/em&gt; and as they appear in &lt;em&gt;Spring&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To secure the point I’m moving towards, compare these images, taken from the appearance of “The Tropics in New York” in &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt; (top) and &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; (bottom): &lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;My thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/nickmimic&#34;&gt;Nicholas Morris&lt;/a&gt; who takes no responsibility for this conjecture, but was enormously helpful in discussing its plausibility.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/harlem-shadows/tropics_compared.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/harlem-shadows/tropics_compared.png&#34; alt=&#34;Comparison of &#39;Tropics in New York&#39; in both SPRING IN NEW HAMPSHIRE and CAMBRIDGE MAGAZINE.&#34; title=&#34;Comparison of two Appearances&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see that imperfection in the ‘I’ of “I could no more gaze” in both versions. Does they look identical to you too? It seems reasonable to conjecture that the &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt; poems and &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; were both printed, if not from a single setting of type, then at least from a setting of type which likely included some of the same typeset material (in either monotype, linotype, or set by hand) from the &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;In the interest of full disclosure, there is a &lt;a href=&#34;/images/harlem-shadows/when-dawn_comparison.png&#34;&gt;similar imperfection&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt; text of “When Dawn Comes to the City” which does not appear in the &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt;; but this does not vitiate the possibility, and evidence, suggesting the two texts represent something like a single setting of type.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The circumstances surrounding &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt; likewise seem to confirm this possibility. &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, at the time, was run by C. K. Ogden, with whom McKay spent time while visiting England in 1920. Ogden ran the magazine in collaboration with a number of his friends (among them, I. A. Richards). Of Ogden, McKay would write in his autobiography &lt;em&gt;A Long Way from Home&lt;/em&gt;: “besides steering me round the picture galleries and being otherwise kind, [Ogden] had published a set of my verses in his &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt;. Later he got me a publisher” (71). If McKay means that Ogden secured the publisher for &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; (and that seems the most likely meaning here), it would certainly make sense that Ogden would go through the same publishing channels (including, perhaps, the same printer) as for the periodical for which he was responsible. &lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;The frontmatter of &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; (published by Grant Richards), lists the printer as “The Morland Press.”&lt;/span&gt; And while Ogden (according to Josh Gosciak) authored the prefatory note for the appearance of the poems in &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, it was I. A. Richards (a friend of Ogden’s, who regularly appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Cambridge Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, including the Summer 1920 issue in which McKay’s poems appeared) who wrote the note the &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; (after, according to McKay, George Bernard Shaw declined to write such an introductory note, &lt;em&gt;Long Way Home&lt;/em&gt; 55).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of which is interesting and worthy of note insomuch as it suggests that &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;, key document of the Harlem Renaissance, has its origins not only in Jamaica and New York, but in New Hampshire and London. This eclecticism was vital to Ogden’s interest in McKay; Ogden was at this moment, working with I. A. Richards on what would emerge as “Basic English.” In &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basic_English&#34;&gt;BASIC&lt;/a&gt;, “Ogden wanted a usable language that reflected the hybridity of the changing dynamic of cultures and languages in the Caribbean, Africa, the United States, and Asia” (Gosciak 102). And in McKay, Ogden believed he had found a uniquely valuable voice in the development of such a language—a language, Gosciak describes, which would “decolonize the dominant ideology that espoused war and imperialism” (103).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, the way in which McKay and Ogden imagined this decolonization of English is somewhat surprising. McKay came to Ogden frustrated with what he perceived to be the limitations of his previously published poetry, in Jamacian dialect. Here is Gosciak again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[McKay’s] reputation was as the “Bobby Burns” of Jamaican folk wisdom, who could write persuasive “love songs” in a sonorous dialect. But an exasperated McKay explained to Ogden: “One can’t express any deep thought to perfection in it, nor can it effectively bring forth the note of sorrow.” Dialect was hackneyed, McKay concluded. “I’ve buried it and don’t care to revive it again.” Ogden was sympathetic to the poet’s desires to internationalize his poetics, and he mentioned him in precision and exactness—de-emotionalizing his lyrics of the charged baggage of Harlem and race. (104)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tension is manifest in a disagreement between Ogden and McKay over what to title the collection. Ogden was interested in developing an international English, Gosciak, drawing on material in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://library.mcmaster.ca/archives/findaids/findaids/o/ogden.htm&#34;&gt;Papers of CK Ogden&lt;/a&gt; explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McKay was opposed to [the title] &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire, and Other Poems&lt;/em&gt;; he believed the title conjured associations with New England, which he felt was “played out”… McKay preferred “a terse, simple thing” for a title, such as “Poems or Verse,” which Ogden, too, appreciated. But McKay also had an eye for the New York—and Harlem—reading public. He suggested “Dawn in New York,” invoking imagery that would ultimately give texture to &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt; in 1922. Ogden persisted in his claims for the high lyricism of Frost, and eventually McKay came around to that aesthetic ground. (The choice of title, &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt;, was, as McKay acknowledged, a bold move for a poet who would very soon reprsent the Harlem Renaissance.) (Gosciak 105)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is sort of confusion of motivations here; McKay’s frustration with dialect and Ogden’s attempt to decolonize English both find expression of in the poems of &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt;—poems that rely on traditional forms—sonnets aplenty!—and frequently Victorian diction. Yet, Ogden’s vision of de-colonizing English also involves de-racinating, with the effect that Ogden preferred to see McKay’s verse avoid any allusion too direct to Harlem or race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; ends up being as notable for what it &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; share with &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt; as what it does. The most famous poem of &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;, “If We Must Die,” had first appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Liberator&lt;/em&gt; in 1919, but it was not included in &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt;. In &lt;em&gt;A Long Way Home&lt;/em&gt;, McKay recounts bringing a copy of &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; to Frank Harris, of &lt;em&gt;Pearson’s Magazine&lt;/em&gt; (who had wanted to publish “If We Must Die,” though he lost out to &lt;em&gt;The Liberator&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Harris] was pleased that I had put over the publication of a book of poems in London. “It’s a hard, mean city for any kind of genius,” he said, “and that’s an achivement for you.” He looked through the little brown-covered book. Then he ran his finger down the table of contents, closely scrutinizing. I noticed his aggressive brow becoem heavier and scowling. Suddenly he roared: “Where is the poem?… That fighting poem, ‘If We Must Die.’ Why isn’t it printed here?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was ashamed. My face was scorched with fire. I stammered: “I was advised to keep it out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You are a bloody traitor to your race, sir!” Frank Harris shouted. “A damned traitor to your own integrity. That’s what the English and civilization have done to your people. Emasculated them. Deprived them of their guts. Better you were a head-hunting, blood-drinking cannibal of the jungle than a civilized coward. You were bolder in America. The English make obscene sycophants of their subject peoples. I am Irish and I know. But we Irish have guts you cannot rip out of us. I am ashamed of you, sir. It’s a good thing you got out of Engliand. It is no place for a genius to live.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank Harris’s words cut like a whip into my hide, and I was glad to get out of his uncomfortable presence. Yet I felt relieved after his castigation. The excision of the poem had been like a nerve cut out of me, leaving a wound which would not heal. And it hurt more every time I saw the damned book of verse. I resolved to plug hard for the publication of an American edition, which would include the omitted poem. (81-82)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McKay here ends up being caught between two white editors, and their respective ways of imagining a response to British colonialism. (This situation recalls that of McKay and his relationship to dialect poetry discussed in Michael North’s excellent chapter in &lt;em&gt;The Dialect of Modernism&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That American edition that McKay resolves to publish after this encounter with Harris would, of course, be &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;, in McKay’s depiction, is a &lt;em&gt;version&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; and a repudiation of it. Elsewhere in his autobiography he writes, “I was full and overflowing with singing and I sang all moods, wild, sweet, and bitter. I was steadfastly pursuing one object: the publication of an American book of verse. I desired to see ‘If We Must Die,’ the sonnet I had omitted in the London volume, inside of a book” (116).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, if McKay’s comments encourage us to read &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt; as a re-politicized version of &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt;, “If We Must Die” itself, nevertheless, famously operates by abstracting the political violence of the “Red Summer” of 1919 into an unspecified “we kinsmen” against a “common foe.” And, indeed, &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;, like &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt;, does not include some of McKay’s most explicitly political poetry of this period—poems like &lt;a href=&#34;http://harlemshadows.org/beta/index.html#supp_mckay_to-the-white-fiends&#34;&gt;“To the White Fiends”&lt;/a&gt; or “A Capitalist at Dinner,” which were initially published in the same period, and in the same venues, as poems like “If We Must Die,” remain excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of which indicates the value of a comprehensive collection of all the contemporary poems and material which went into the making of &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt;—both through their inclusion and their exclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;appendix-tables-of-contents-compared&#34;&gt;Appendix: Tables of Contents Compared&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below I’ve preserved the original orderings of the tables of contents for both &lt;em&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/em&gt; and used color (a lovely salmon) to indicate which titles are shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Harlem Shadows&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Spring in New Hampshire&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
The Easter Flower
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Spring in New Hampshire
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
To One Coming North
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Spanish Needle
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
America
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Lynching
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Alfonso, Dressing to Wait at Table
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
To O. E. A.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Tropics in New York
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
Alfonso, Dressing to Wait at Table, Sings
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Flame Heart
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
Flowers of Passion
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Home Thoughts
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
To Work
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
On Broadway
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Morning Joy
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Barrier
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
Reminiscences
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Adolescence
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
On Broadway
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Homing Swallows
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
Love Song
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
The City’s Love
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
North and South
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
North and South
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Rest in Peace
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Wild May
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
A Memory of June
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
The Plateau
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
To Winter
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
After the Winter
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Winter in the Country
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
The Wild Goat
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
After the Winter
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Harlem Shadows
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Tropics in New York
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
The White City
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
I Shall Return
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Spanish Needle
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Castaways
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
My Mother
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
December 1919
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
In Bondage
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
Flame-Heart
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
December, 1919
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
In Bondage
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Heritage
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Harlem Shadows
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
When I Have Passed Away
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Harlem Dancer
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Enslaved
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
A Prayer
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
I Shall Return
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Barrier
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Morning Joy
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
When Dawn Comes to the City
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Africa
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
The Choice
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
On a Primitive Canoe
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
Sukee River
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Winter in the Country
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#40e0d0&#34;&gt;
Exhortation
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
To Winter
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Spring in New Hampshire
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
On the Road
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Harlem Dancer
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Dawn in New York
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
The Tired Worker
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Outcast
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
I Know My Soul
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Birds of Prey
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Castaways
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Exhortation: Summer, 1919
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
The Lynching
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Baptism
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
If We Must Die
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Subway Wind
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
The Night Fire
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Poetry
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
To a Poet
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
A Prayer
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
When Dawn Comes to the City
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
O Word I Love to Sing
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Absence
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Summer Morn in New Hampshire
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
Rest in Peace
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
A Red Flower
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Courage
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
To O. E. A.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Romance
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Flower of Love
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
The Snow Fairy
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
La Paloma in London
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
A Memory of June
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Flirtation
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Tormented
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Polarity
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
One Year After
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
French Leave
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Jasmines
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Commemoration
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Memorial
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Thirst
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Futility
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#adff2f&#34;&gt;
Through Agony
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;background-color:#ffa07a&#34;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;works-cited&#34;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gosciak, Josh. &lt;em&gt;The Shadowed Country: Claude Mckay and the Romance of the Victorians.&lt;/em&gt; New Brunswick, N.J.: Rutgers University Press, 2006. Print.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;McKay, Claude. &lt;em&gt;A Long Way from Home&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Gene Andrew Jarrett. New Brunswick, N.J.: Rutgers University Press, 2007. Print.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </content>
</entry>


<entry>
    <title>Somewhere in New Jersey...</title>
    
    <link rel="via" type="text/html" href="cforster.com//2013/09/sysadmin-for-poets" />
    
    <id>tag:cforster.com,2013-09-27:/2013/09/sysadmin-for-poets</id>
    <updated>2013-09-27T00:12:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;/2013/08/teaching-dh&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; on a graduate course I taught last Spring, I mentioned the server I ended up using a way to try to establish some uniformity of access to software packages and tools. In this post, I’
    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Forster</name>
    </author>
    
    
    <content type="html">
    	&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;/2013/08/teaching-dh&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; on a graduate course I taught last Spring, I mentioned the server I ended up using a way to try to establish some uniformity of access to software packages and tools. In this post, I’ll try to add a few details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;virtual-private-servers&#34;&gt;Virtual Private Servers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to understand about “the server” is that I rented a &lt;em&gt;VPS&lt;/em&gt;, a “virtual(ized) private server,” rather than some shared space. If you don’t know what that means, let me try to explain (if you do know what that means, you may want to move along to the next section).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;em&gt;server&lt;/em&gt; itself is one of the slipperier bits of our contemporary argot. It can name a number of different links in a relationship between one piece of software and another (to say nothing of the people on either end, or perhaps in between). This slipperiness is only compounded with the advent of &lt;em&gt;virtual private servers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to virtualization, if you wanted to host a webpage, you could either run (or rent) your own dedicated hardware, or you go with a “shared hosting” option. For most folks who run their own blog, shared hosting remains the obvious choice. This blog is hosted on such a shared host. Shared hosting relies on a few facts:&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LAMP&lt;/strong&gt;: that is Linux (an operating system to manage the hardware resources, to schedule processes… you know, to turn electricity, plastic, and rare earth elements into a computer), Apache (the most widely used web server), MySQL (the most widely used database; which has its own database &lt;em&gt;server&lt;/em&gt;), and (usually) PHP (a scripting language).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most folks’ hosting needs can be solved by a single “stack” of common software, usually the so-called &lt;strong&gt;LAMP&lt;/strong&gt; stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most folks’ blogs don’t get sufficient traffic to require that much hardware, and so many blogs (websites, whatever) can be “served” by a single (“shared”) host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the OS can easily separate out different users; that way, I can run Wordpress and create a database, and you can run Drupal and create a database, all on the same hardware, without either of us being able to destroy one another’s data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drawback to shared hosting is that you have very little control over the server. You usually can’t, for instance, install new software, beyond packages of PHP scripts. Of course, for web hosting, that’s no big deal; you don’t really need to install anything beyond whatever CMS you want anyway. &lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;Anyone who has had problems with a web host’s version of PHP, or similar issues, knows that this isn’t quite true.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This compromise with respect to control over the server configuration is a function of cost (and of course, expertise; do you really want to have to worry about building that “software stack?”). To have complete control over a server would mean that you had a dedicated server (in this case, “server” means actual &lt;em&gt;hardware&lt;/em&gt;), perhaps in your office (in theory it could be your laptop), in an IT closet, or rented in a server farm somewhere. With the advent of software virtualization, however, this changed. With virtualization, a single piece of hardware can run multiple “virtual machines”; the host system simulates another machine, on which you can then run software which itself doesn’t really know the difference. (If you run Windows on a Mac with Parallels, this idea may be quite familiar.) You can do the same thing with a server. That computer that talked to the internet, and served web pages (or whatever), is not just a &lt;em&gt;virtual&lt;/em&gt; machine. And such a virtualized private server (a VPS, as opposed to a &lt;em&gt;shared&lt;/em&gt; host) reconfigures the costs involve, and makes it more affordable to give you more control over the software installed, without incurring the full cost of owning/renting/running an actual physical hardware server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A virtualized server is (&lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; significantly) cheaper than running your own hardware, but allows you many of the advantages of actually running your own hardware. It is still, in general, more expensive than shared hosting. To give you some sense of the cost, the lowest tier &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com/&#34;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; VPS is $20/month. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/pricing&#34;&gt;Digital Ocean’s lowest tier&lt;/a&gt; is only $5/month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-customized-server&#34;&gt;A Customized Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it is so customizable, I thought a VPS could offer a solution to the challenge of trying to make software uniformly available to students enrolled in the digital humanities seminar I was teaching. With such a system I could give everyone access to Python and the NLTK (and its associated corpora) without having to ask folks to install that software on their own machines. I could install MALLET and R (and relevant R packages) and Stanford’s Named Entity Recognizer and an XSLT processor. This was also a relatively flexible solution; if someone wanted to try something else, perhaps something I’d never heard of, it was in many easy to install it on the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; in that last sentence is a function of Linux package management. If you’re used to installing from .EXEs (or .DMGs) you download from the web, the world of package management can seem arcane. However, for large pieces of software, package management systems are wonderful and can be (deceptively) simple to use. While getting everything up and running is a bit of a trick (you need to first install an operating system—about which a little more below—and then some basic software to let you connect to the server), installing a piece of software, like the R language, is as simple as typing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{%highlight bash %} sudo apt-get install r-base {%endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, you have R installed, and you’re ready to go at the command line. In my experience, Linux package management is often &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; than trying to handle software dependencies on other OSes (at least once you’re familiar with conventions of your package management system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Easy&lt;/em&gt; is also relative; if you’re comfortable at the command line, using a package manager feels intellectually more intuitive and comprehensible than dragging a DMG into an “Applications” folder, or double-clicking an EXE. But if you’re uncomfortable with the command line, this will likely feel as uncomfortable as navigating your filesystem or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;server-setup&#34;&gt;Server Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you can install packages, though you need to first install a base, Linux operating system. If you’re unfamiliar with Linux, this may not be the kindest or easiest way to get acquainted with it, though the good folks at Linode (hardly unbiased) insist &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com/faq.cfm&#34;&gt;“If you’re looking to learn, there is no better environment. Experiment with the different Linux flavors, redeploy from scratch in a matter of minutes.”&lt;/a&gt;. I have spent too much of my life playing with Linux distros, and so this part of the process felt quite natural. And yet, I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; managed to make what I now consider a wrong choice in configuring the server. Linux comes in a wide array of flavors or distributions.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;Technically, “Linux” is not an OS, but an OS “kernel.” This distinction, and what we call things, can get &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNU/Linux_naming_controversy&#34;&gt;contentious&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; Of the options Linode offers (Ubuntu, Arch, OpenSuse, Gentoo, CentOS, Slackware, Debian, Fedora) I opted for Debian. Debian has a reputation for being a very stable distro; and so it would be a great choice for running a web-server. Of course, I &lt;em&gt;wasn’t&lt;/em&gt; running a web and so stability was not, in fact, my &lt;em&gt;chief&lt;/em&gt; concern. I probably should have chosen a distribution which prioritized not stability, but the ease and availability of new and up-to-date software packages. Arch Linux, with its “rolling release” schedule (and the operating system &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mylinuxrig.com/post/11831613369/the-linux-setup-chris-forster-academic&#34;&gt;I once loved&lt;/a&gt; with a passion I’ve not since been able to match) would have made more sense. It would have been &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; with Arch to install the most update versions of certain Python packages, etc etc. Oh well. Maybe next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’re base OS is installed; it’s time to install the basic packages you will need to do &lt;em&gt;anything at all&lt;/em&gt;. But since you now are responsible for a computer somewhere in New Jersey&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;I must say, the responsiveness of the Linode servers shocked me; that computer in NJ was consistently more responsive than my home media server. I regularly ran emacs sessions &lt;em&gt;on the server&lt;/em&gt; and found them completely responsive.&lt;/span&gt; you need to worry about security. You don’t want someone hijacking your VPS and using to send spam or whatever else. Linode offers &lt;a href=&#34;http://library.linode.com/securing-your-server&#34;&gt;some tips&lt;/a&gt; and I consulted &lt;a href=&#34;http://feross.org/how-to-setup-your-linode/&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; for some advice as well. It wasn’t nearly as scary as I imagined. I installed &lt;code&gt;fail2ban&lt;/code&gt; (and left the default settings), turned off root log-in from ssh, and that was about it. I have (so far) had no problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;connecting-and-interacting-with-the-server&#34;&gt;Connecting and Interacting with the Server&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve sort of glossed over a pretty fundamental fact; with the exception of RStudio server (mentioned below), the only way to interact with the server as I’ve described it is through &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell&#34;&gt;SSH&lt;/a&gt;; and so the only access you have to the server is command line access. For the most part, that was fine for the goals I had for the class. Command line access allowed people to experiment with Python and NLTK; they could run MALLET, and similar things. You couldn’t run, say, Gephi on the server though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this limitation proved frustrating for folks working with film and images. For one thing, moving large movie/image files back and forth to the server would have proved unpleasant; moreover, software like &lt;a href=&#34;http://rsbweb.nih.gov/ij/&#34;&gt;ImageJ&lt;/a&gt; couldn’t be installed on the server and had to be installed locally. (I did manage, though, to do some image manipulation with ImageMagick—here is every page of the &lt;em&gt;Little Review&lt;/em&gt; in a single image (a larger, ~150M, image is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/idnsh1tmkteeevu/lr.png&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/lr_smaller.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/lr_smaller.png&#34; alt=&#34;Little Review Montage&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/lr_montage_close-up.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/lr_montage_close-up.png&#34; alt=&#34;A Close-Up of the Little Review Montage&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For folks who were interested in using &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/ide/docs/server/getting_started&#34;&gt;RStudio Server&lt;/a&gt; worked &lt;em&gt;wonderfully&lt;/em&gt;; it allowed folks to connect to the server through their web browser and have an RStudio Session that looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/rstudio-running.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/rstudio-running.png&#34; alt=&#34;RStudio, Running&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I gripe about &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt;, RStudio is really excellent. If there is comparable server project that will let folks run python and python packages (including matplotlib) through a browser in a similar way, please, &lt;em&gt;please&lt;/em&gt; let me know. RStudio provides a great way to provide a standardized R environment with a common set of shared packages (and perhaps even data) available to all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other things one could do with sort of set-up; if you wanted to run an old-school Bulletin Board System or MUD, you could do it (here are &lt;a href=&#34;http://lunduke.com/?p=2156&#34;&gt;some ideas&lt;/a&gt; about running a BBS system). &lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;You also might look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telnetbbsguide.com/ssh.htm&#34;&gt;The BBS Corner’s Telnet &amp;amp; Dial-Up BBS Guide&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.convolution.us/&#34;&gt;Convolution BBS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; As a way to offer &lt;em&gt;certain&lt;/em&gt; pieces of software to people without requiring them to install them, running this server was very helpful. If you’re doing tasks that can be scripted and which can often take a very long time to complete (such as topic modeling, or named entity extraction, or POS tagging)&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;I would add certain types of image manipulation—as I did with the &lt;em&gt;Little Review&lt;/em&gt; example noted above; though as I say, shuttling the images back and forth can be unpleasant; this unpleasantness is partially allayed if you’re scripting your image acquisition with a script, “a little &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt; magic,” or similar ought to work.&lt;/span&gt; you can set them going, disconnect from the server and then check on them later (using a program like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/software/screen/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;screen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to make this easy; it’s &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; great to be walking to home, knowing that somewhere in New Jersey a computer is dutifully seeking 100 topics across 5000 documents).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve skipped over some of the other unglamorous, sysadminy things one must do: creating user accounts for each person in the class; creating a shared directory that everyone could read and write to; and other things like that. For someone comfortable at the command line, and interested to learn, all of that stuff is entirely manageable.&lt;/p&gt;

    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </content>
</entry>


<entry>
    <title>On &#34;Teaching&#34; &#34;Digital Humanities&#34;</title>
    
    <link rel="via" type="text/html" href="cforster.com//2013/08/teaching-dh" />
    
    <id>tag:cforster.com,2013-08-23:/2013/08/teaching-dh</id>
    <updated>2013-08-23T00:12:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;As this academic year warms up, some thoughts on the last one; last year I had the unexpected opportunity to teach a graduate seminar in the Spring.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;I was not as diligent as a blog coordinator, keeping up with sum
    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Forster</name>
    </author>
    
    
    <content type="html">
    	&lt;p&gt;As this academic year warms up, some thoughts on the last one; last year I had the unexpected opportunity to teach a graduate seminar in the Spring.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;I was not as diligent as a blog coordinator, keeping up with summary posts, as I would have liked, but some summaries and links to student blogs are available &lt;a href=&#34;http://630dh.cforster.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; I wavered between a theories of modernism course (think: Hugh Kenner, Peter Burger, Frederic Jameson, Susan Stanford Friedman) and an “Intro DH” class, settling on the latter simply because I thought it would be more valuable to graduate students (few of whom, in our department, have strong research interests in modernist studies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course benefited from a number of sources; one is Scott Weingart’s excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scottbot.net/HIAL/?page_id=21794&#34;&gt;list of DH syllabi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;He says syllabi; I say syllabuses; it is a battle that has &lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=syllabi%2Csyllabuses&amp;amp;year_start=1800&amp;amp;year_end=2000&amp;amp;corpus=15&amp;amp;smoothing=3&amp;amp;share=&#34;&gt;raged for centuries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; I should also thank a number of people who were kind enough to offer thoughts (and sometimes texts) as I put together the syllabus: Stéfan Sinclair, David Golumbia, and Brian Lennon offered suggestions. They were all more than generous; though, of course, they bear no responsibility for whatsoever for the syllabus. I also was fortunate enough to end up corresponding with a number of other folks during the semester, thanks to all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in seeing the syllabus, you can see it in &lt;a href=&#34;/files/eng630_syllabus-final.pdf&#34;&gt;[PDF]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/files/eng630_syllabus-final.html&#34;&gt;[HTML]&lt;/a&gt;, or (heaven help you) on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/c-forster/eng630-syllabus&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;In theory, the whole github syllabuses thing sounds promising; and for DH stuff, who knows? But really, just putting the stuff on the web is probably the best way to share teaching materials.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The syllabus includes, at least to some extent, basically all the texts that, a while back, Brian Croxall mentioned as the “usual” DH reading list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/digiwonk&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;digiwonk&#34;&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;digiwonk?&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/readywriting&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;readywriting&#34;&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;readywriting?&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Graphs, Maps, Trees would be first. Then Debates, two Blackwell books. Ramsay, Jockers, Kirschenbaum. The usual.
&lt;/p&gt;
— Brian Croxall (&lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;briancroxall&#34;&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;briancroxall?&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/briancroxall/statuses/358076804084416512&#34;&gt;July 19, 2013&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would have &lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt; to use Jockers’s &lt;em&gt;Macroanalysis&lt;/em&gt;, but it was not out in time; I would certainly use it were I to teach the class again. Indeed, I could very easily imagine a class taught around &lt;em&gt;Macroanalysis&lt;/em&gt; as its central text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagined the course as centered by a basically epistemological perspective: does the “becoming digital of textuality” &lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;“becoming digital of textuality” is clumsy; but I think it gets at the thing I’m interested in better than anything else.&lt;/span&gt; change the sorts of knowledge about literature and culture that scholars produce. Does it offer, to put it more polemically, a &lt;em&gt;science&lt;/em&gt; of culture? (I avoided this polemical formulation in class; not least because of the definition of “science” that it assumes). This was the motivation for starting with C.P. Snow’s “The Two Cultures,” a text &lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;I would, in the future, however excerpt Snow; there are a lot more relics of the Cold War in that essay than I recalled, not all of which were directly relevant.&lt;/span&gt; which I sometimes see condescendingly referred to as if it were backward, outdated, or self-evidently wrong, when I find its core thesis remains provocative and at least partially compelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course was then organized around questions of digitization and textual representation&lt;span class=&#34;marginnote&#34;&gt;The Latour and Lowe essay, from &lt;em&gt;Switching Codes&lt;/em&gt; is a real gem, and one I don’t see mentioned very frequently.&lt;/span&gt;, and then a whole slew of things I called distant reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure that there’s anything in my life that I’d call an unmitigated success, and this class is surely no exception. I think though that it did the job of familiarizing folks with at least some of what “DH” is, particularly for folks in English departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if I’ll ever teach such a course again. But here are some things I think I learned—things I’d change and things I’d do the same way again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More, not less, technical:&lt;/strong&gt; I was acutely aware of the worry among students that this class would be “highly technical” and require students to have all sorts of prerequisite knowledge. To avoid that, I think I erred too far on the other side, and set the bar too low. I integrated some tools into class, while leaving the more technical, hands-on stuff for suppelementary (optional) hands-on sessions (we did a little Intro Python &amp;amp; nltk; we did some topic modeling with MALLET, some web-scraping, etc). This was logistically a problem (finding a time that worked for everyone). More fundamentally, my sense is that the class would have been stronger had it been &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; technical. The evaluations seem to confirm this almost unanimously; everyone thought more hands on with software would be a benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would that mean in practice? While we spent time talking about encoding; and looking at some examples of TEI encoded documents (including the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.folgerdigitaltexts.org/&#34;&gt;Folger’s&lt;/a&gt;), we didn’t actually encode anything. But until you’ve had to complete a teiHeader, you don’t really know the burden of metadata. Actually making folks encode a text would be one avenue I might pursue. By selecting texts with a sufficiently interesting textual history and encoding some apparatus, this could be interesting assignment indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mattwilkens.com/2012/12/31/dh-grad-course-reflections/&#34;&gt;Matt Wilkens reports&lt;/a&gt; having success using &lt;a href=&#34;http://programminghistorian.org/lessons&#34;&gt;“The Programming Historian”&lt;/a&gt;; I could imagine doing something similar, and centering the class’s practical activities around Python (about which more below); I would do so despite serious reservations about both my own qualification to be teaching such material (I am, after all, an autodidact in these matters) and the utility that a superficial command of a scripting language would give a graduate student in English.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Tool Well&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a corollary to the previous point; more technical, but also more focused. As we moved through the semester, the variety of different software packages we looked at increased: basic word frequencies with command line tools, R (particularly for mapping), MALLET, Stanford’s Named Entity Recognizer, Python (with a number of libraries—particularly the NLTK), ImageJ, and others. There is a value to examining a diversity of software tools; but its costs, upon reflection, now seem too high. For someone coming to such technologies for the very first time, I think focusing on one, very flexible technology to do all (or at least most) of the things we would be interested in doing might be the best approach. And Python could fit the bill; certain things may be less pleasant in Python, but overall the consistency of a single language and syntax would have been a virtue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I will say that while I think I’d prefer Python over R, &lt;em&gt;if you were to use R&lt;/em&gt;, running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/ide/docs/server/getting_started&#34;&gt;RStudio Server&lt;/a&gt; would be a great way to provide a consistent software base for students; as a piece of software, it was pretty stellar. Speaking of which…)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Running a Server? Totally Worth It&lt;/strong&gt;: One of problems in a class like this is infrastructure; you want folks to be able to play with some of these tools, but trying to get MALLET, or Python plus a handful of libraries, installed on students’ machines can be very unpleasant. To create some consistency in the software available to folks and to avoid having to try to install software packages on 6 different OS versions and hardware platforms, I rented some server space with Linode (approximate cost: $25/month) and set up user accounts for everyone. Then I installed all the software packages we would be interested in using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a setup utterly lacks any GUI (unless you count browser access to something like RStudio), which requires folks to be comfortable at the command line. This was no small thing. Use of the server was essentially optional, and some folks simply never got interested in it. In the spirit of “more, not less, technical” I’d probably require more engagement with the server in a second version. I’ll write up a more detailed explanation of the server set up I used soon; but this worked, over all, very well, and with some tweaks could work even better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’d Probably Require Twitter&lt;/strong&gt;: I suggested folks have a twitter account, but didn’t require it. The folks who were on twitter, though benefited from it (I think); it provided an additional shared context; when authors we were reading were on twitter or had blogs, I was sure to note it, and I sometimes saw the extra context folks had gleaned from these resources in their contributions to class.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I planned the syllabus, I was concerned to try to integrate criticism of “DH” into this class, to make it both a class &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; “digital humanities” as well as a digital humanities class. I wanted to leaven ambient excitement or “buzz” with skepticism, to use the tools but to do so with care and reflection, to balance the hacking with yacking (to invoke a short-hand that has produced much hand-wringing). I will say, however, that during class meetings, I generally found myself working harder to overcome the skepticism, rather than to contain the excitement; wanting there to indeed be a little less yack and a little more…&lt;/p&gt;

    	
    	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cforster.com/"&gt;Permalink&lt;/p&gt;
    	
    </content>
</entry>


</feed>